[opening theme playing]
[tapping on door]
Open up, love.
I brought more things
for you and the baby.
Got some fresh eggs and bread.
I'll leave it here.
[baby crying]
-Ada, think of the little one.
-Shh.
Babies don't have principles.
[baby cooing]
[baby crying]
Did you speak to her?
She didn't speak back.
Well, did you tell her?
I'll only tell her what I know to be true.
It's the last time I am going to say this.
It wasn't me who shopped Freddie Thorne.
Tommy.
I'd ask you to swear on the Bible,
but you can't swear on that, can you?
Nothing you hold sacred.
There's tea.
The new system.
Everything in the diary, eh?
Mm-hmm.
Black star. What does that mean?
The black star day
is the day we take out
Billy Kimber and his men.
No one knows this.
Not even your family?
Grace.
Everyone in my family hates me.
Why would I tell them?
He's off the bloody rails is what he is.
If he'll turn nose on his best mate...
Bloody neighbors, John.
Snitch behind the curtain.
Yeah, well, if you think that,
you're the only one who does.
Look at this, look.
Bloody raking it in.
Who's running this carny?
Name of Marston.
Intends on wintering
in Small Heath with this ring.
-Does he?
-Only heard.
Nobody in Small Heath craps in a pot
without the decree of Tommy Almighty.
Mr. Marston, I believe. The ringmaster!
-Proud I am to say so.
-Yes, well,
these here are civilized parts.
Man wants to set his stall up
with fellas lamping each other,
he needs himself a license.
A license?
For a fee. From those in charge.
[men cheering]
I'll tell you what.
How about I keep my money,
and you shove a license
up your arse crack?
You don't want to speak to me like that.
And who the bloody hell
do you think you are?
My name is Arthur Shelby!
Dad?
Jesus!
Thank you. You are a good boy.
Bless thee, Father, for these bounties
we are about to receive--
Jesus Christ.
Please, woman, not in vain.
Finish your sandwich and sling your hook.
Pollyanna. I'm the guest
of the head of this family,
so why don't you maybe tend
to your mangle or your scuttle?
The head of the family ain't here.
Tommy.
He sometimes helps me
with... with business, Dad.
[door opens, closes]
Aye, well, speak of the devil.
How are you, son?
Get out.
Come on, son.
I'm a changed man.
This family needed you ten years ago,
and you walked out on us.
Not now. Get out of this house.
-Tommy, he's different--
-Shut up.
It's all right, son.
Arthur Shelby never stays
where he's not welcome.
Quite something you've become.
Bye, son.
He's our dad.
[sighs]
He's a selfish bastard.
You calling someone a selfish bastard,
that's a bit rich, Tommy.
I mean, thanks to you,
we're already down a bloody sister.
You want to see him, Arthur?
You want to see him?
You go with him.
[door opens, slams]
Grace, I am taking five pounds
from petty cash, all right?
[Grace] We don't have
five pounds in petty cash.
Then I'll take what we've got.
Count it and leave a receipt.
Arthur, there are things
in these books I don't understand.
-Likewise.
-Every week we pay one pound ten shilling
by postal order
to a Daniel Owen in London.
Danny Whizz-Bang, hangs around
the pubs in Camden Town Wharf for us.
Keeps his ears open for business.
He's a good man.
I thought Danny Whizz-Bang was dead.
Then you thought wrong, didn't you?
But I've seen his grave. He was shot.
That was a show to satisfy the wops.
Tommy just shot
some sheep's brains at him.
Who's buried in his grave?
Now, look, Grace,
if you know what's good for you,
you don't ask questions
about things that don't concern you.
Never. Right?
That's for you.
And don't tell Tommy I took this!
The boy needs a good hiding,
if you ask me.
Yeah, well, Aunt Polly's
close to giving him one.
John and Ada, too, it sounds like.
John moans on bloody principle.
But if you saw his missus...
You have a girl yourself, son?
Perhaps when it suits Tommy, eh?
Yeah, well, he's been different,
you know, since the war.
Yeah, well, a war can change a man.
Speaking for myself, anyway.
Where did you fight, Dad?
Ah, all over, son, all over.
Yeah, all over.
Then the salvation of Jesus Christ
spread His light over me,
and as a pilgrim,
I come to visit the New World.
America.
Where I beheld the future.
Casinos. Money factories, son.
Look, I've been studying the competition,
their schemes,
their systems. Look at that.
-Show me.
-It's all there.
There's a fortune to be made here.
I'm an old man,
and my heart's a battered vessel.
But within...
there still beats
the fluttering pulse of a dream.
The Shelby Casino and Hotel.
Gents and dames
will come flocking from all corners.
New York, Chicago, Boston.
To the Shelby,
where I can stand proudly
with my dear children by my side.
And the women there!
Like fresh peaches.
Thou could have a dozen.
We'd all of us be kings!
How much? How much to get started?
The oak needs but an acorn.
Let's do it.
Let's do it. Let's bloody do it.
It would make my heart beam,
but I don't want to cause
any discord between the brothers.
So, please, why don't you
talk to Tommy first.
No, no, I'm sick of taking
orders from him.
Tommy's not the only one
in the family with a head for business.
And Shelby money is Shelby money.
I thank God for my wonderful sons.
This is cause for a celebration!
-Yeah.
-Sláinte!
Sláinte!
On your feet, soldier.
On your feet!
[all shouting]
I don't want to fight you, Dad.
Come on, boy!
I'm old enough to be your father.
On your feet.
Get up!
All right!
Is that all you've got, boy?
Get up!
This here is Arthur Shelby Jr.!
My son! I love him, and I'm proud of him.
And he can fight any one of youse in here!
[crowd cheering]
You did good, son. You did good.
I love you, Dad! I love you!
Mr. Shelby?
Who's asking?
My name is Byrne.
I had word from your man
in Camden Town you wanted to parley.
Then parley it is.
A few months ago,
a man named Ryan came to this place
with a view to buying
some goods from you.
Mr. Ryan met with an accident.
He was shot.
I heard.
[Byrne] He was a man
with a quick mouth. I know that.
I wondered if he made
any enemies in here.
None that I know of.
It's not the kind of place
to make enemies.
All are welcome here, Mr. Byrne.
Including Irish?
Oh, especially Irish.
Ryan told you he was a member
of the Irish Republican Army.
Was he still welcome?
Like I say, any man
that buys beer is welcome.
Perhaps you didn't believe him.
In pubs, sometimes people say things,
sometimes it's the whiskey talking.
It's hard to tell which is which.
As a teetotal man, I find that amusing.
Except when it ends in tragedy.
Would you like some water
and cordial, Mr. Byrne?
You see, Mr. Shelby,
Ryan, for all his quick mouth,
was indeed connected.
Very well connected to our brotherhood.
By membership and blood.
He was my cousin.
I am from South Armagh.
I'm a man of influence there.
Cordial and water
would be grand, Mr. Shelby.
Grace, bring some water and cordial
to the snug.
-This way.
-Yes, Mr. Shelby.
My cousin came to buy guns.
And I told him I have none.
Your man, Danny Owen,
talks a lot when he's drunk.
He says the Peaky Blinders
do have the guns.
Robbed from the factory down the road.
He boasts about
a stack of Lewis machine guns
and enough belts of ammunition
to hold up God's trousers.
Yep. That sounds like our Danny.
He has an imagination.
Like I say, sometimes it's the whiskey
that does the talking.
He says only the brothers know
where the guns are kept.
Well, Danny also says
he sees German infantrymen
on the back of mill carts.
And he shoots them with his broomstick.
We have men in the BSA factory.
They say it's you who has them.
And we have men
who work in the police station.
Every finger, Mr. Shelby.
Every finger in this city
points in one direction.
Please don't mistake me for a fool.
Let me get to the point.
I don't care what kind
of half-arsed tinker operation
you have going here.
But I can assure you,
I represent a very different category
of organization.
My cousin was shot.
I am judge, jury and executioner.
I find you guilty, and I pass sentence.
You deliver the guns to me,
or I deliver death and hell's fury to you
and your little tribe of heathens.
Am I making myself clear?
Let me confess something to you.
And only to you.
I have the guns,
but they have become a burden to me.
Perhaps it is time to unload that burden.
For the right price.
[clears throat]
[Campbell] Malacki Byrne.
Brigade commander
of the South Armagh IRA.
You hooked yourself a big fish there.
With these guns as bait,
who knows what we'll catch?
"We."
Are you suggesting that you and I
could work together as a team?
Perhaps we have more in common
than you think, Inspector.
Can you deliver him?
With your help.
And I want word put out in Ireland
that I was not involved.
[Campbell] So I'd be solving
a problem for you.
-And I'd be winning you that medal.
-[laughs]
If I get a medal,
I will have your initials
engraved on the backside.
My initials on your backside.
That's quite an image.
Inspector, since we're getting on so well,
can you answer me a question?
Who gave you Freddie Thorne?
As everyone in the city knows,
it was you, Mr. Shelby.
[tapping on door]
Hello, son.
It's all there.
It is indeed.
We're gonna build something
with this, son.
Something magnificent.
When do we sail, Dad?
-Hungry for work, are you?
-Yeah.
A ship sails Friday.
Meet me at the boxing ring.
Good. Friday.
Friday.
[banging on door]
Leave that open.
No.
-Are you expecting trouble?
-Yeah.
-At this hour?
-Midnight is as good an hour as any.
What the hell is going on?
When the St. Andrew's bell
strikes midnight,
two IRA men are gonna come
through that door.
When they have what they want,
they plan to kill me.
It's your job to stop that happening.
You could've given me some more warning.
I just got the message myself.
-They want to meet here alone.
-And barmaids don't count?
No. Barmaids don't count.
Now, you're gonna be in that back room.
I'm gonna be sitting there.
When I make a toast,
you're gonna come out
with that thing raised.
You don't shoot. You just point.
I'll do the rest.
-Will you kill them?
-No, the police want them alive.
-The police know about this?
-Look, just hold it up.
Just point. Right?
All right, go. Go on. Go!
[bell dinging]
We'll hold back here.
If damage is done to either side,
it's no concern of ours.
Lost your thirst, eh?
Just show us where.
Give me the cash.
You're gonna need a shovel.
[chuckles]
You thick fucking tinker.
Did you think we'd let you live?
Make your peace, Mr. Shelby.
I will make my peace my own way.
To barmaids who don't count.
[both grunting]
[breathing heavily]
Why did you shoot?
Why did you shoot, Grace?
I didn't know I had it in me like that.
Now you've seen me.
And you've seen me.
I'm sorry.
You were supposed to come
on the sixth chime.
on the fucking sixth chime!
They refused to surrender.
They fought well. They were brave men.
Well, he looks like he was killed
by a wild fucking animal.
Still, this never happened.
They were never here. Who cares?
Get the bodies out of here.
Ah, right, are they making
the lady uncomfortable?
I'll leave you two lovebirds
to it, then, eh?
Thank you.
I'm sorry.
First of all, let me say,
I had no idea he would involve you
in this ugly business.
If I had, I never
would have let it happen.
He trusts me. I told you that.
You didn't believe me.
Fine.
Sergeant Moss made a report,
which, of course, I burnt.
He said, when he entered
the room, you were embracing.
Is that your primary concern?
An embrace?
No, my concern is for your welfare.
It was me who killed them.
I had no control.
You have been living with beasts.
It was the beast that tried to stop me.
I believe last night
something inside me changed.
I no longer feel the need
to avenge my father.
The hatred that I brought here
with me is gone.
And therefore, my reasons
for joining the service.
You want to resign?
I think our mission
has come to a natural end.
I think I know where the guns are hidden.
You do? So tell me where.
If I'm right and the guns are found,
you have no more business
with Thomas Shelby. Is that not so?
Our military mission will be over,
and we can leave the city as we found it.
Are you trying to do a deal with me?
Because if you are, you must be explicit.
I want your word that Thomas Shelby
will not be harmed
if the guns are recovered.
Your word as a gentleman.
Will you give it?
Now, why would you want to save him?
A residue of sympathy.
Sympathy? You mean sentiment?
Yes.
In his way, he has been kind to me.
-Sentiment.
-Yes.
You're too good-hearted for this work.
Perhaps.
So, for my sake, will you spare him?
You have my word.
A week after the robbery,
there was a burial
at St. Andrew's churchyard.
I have found out that the man
supposed to be buried is alive.
Arthur is quite transparent.
I learned that the funeral was
attended only by the brothers.
And the grave that they dug
was far deeper than your average
and lined with lead.
To keep out the damp.
The guns are buried in that grave.
Then tonight we will dig up that grave.
[Grace] ♪ When my family thinks ♪
♪ That I'm safely in my bed ♪
♪ Oh, from morn until night ♪
♪ I am stretched out at your head ♪
♪ Calling out unto the earth ♪
♪ With tears hot and wild ♪
♪ For the loss of a boy ♪
♪ That I loved as a child ♪
♪ So I am stretched on your grave ♪
♪ And I'll lie here forever ♪
♪ If your hands were in mine ♪
♪ I'd be sure they would not sever ♪
♪ My apple tree, my brightness ♪
♪ It's time we were together ♪
Well done, boys.
♪ For I smell of the earth ♪
♪ And I'm worn by the weather ♪
All but one gun accounted for.
Then, sir, I resign my commission.
Good.
So I am no longer your superior officer,
and you are no longer my subordinate.
And therefore,
regulations permit me to offer you this.
I'm a... I'm a simple man but a good man.
And my admiration for you
has turned to love.
I don't ask for love in return. Just...
recognition that we are like minds
with shared values.
Grace,
will you marry me?
Mr. Campbell...
you deserve better.
Is it him between us?
Is it the beast that dug that grave?
Is it him?!
My resignation will be with you
in the morning.
Dad?
Hello, son.
May I ask who gave you
my whereabouts?
Marston.
Said you left him last night
with a bill for your whores.
Well, at least we got to say goodbye, son.
And bid a fond adieu
to your dear brothers, would you?
How could you do this to us?
Do what, son?
All that stuff you said
about the Shelby Casino.
And Atlantic City.
Well, if the truth be told,
I'm not so acquainted
with that promised land
as I had thee believe.
You're a fucking liar and a thief.
You give me back my fucking money!
"Do not despise the thief
who steals to satisfy his starvation."
That's in the Holy Bible, son.
And I have starved for so very long.
Fare thee well, son.
I waited for you.
I waited.
[shouting]
Listen to me, boy.
You are not in the prize ring now.
If you ever put your hands on me again,
I'll cut your fucking throat
and spread you on these tracks.
Where's your father?
I'm assuming he's frittering away
the 500 you took from us
and put in his thieving,
whore-groping hands.
What were you thinking?
How dare you do something like that
without talking to Thomas or me?
Does Tommy know?
No.
But you're gonna tell him.
You might take satisfaction
in a great victory.
A terrible consequence has been avoided.
Those guns that we dug up will never
be used to murder the innocent
or usurp the status quo.
But even though we have solved a crime,
we have as yet failed
to punish the criminal.
This man who dug this grave
has also dug his own.
He has proved a deadly menace
to the King's peace.
And tonight we will strike him down.
We will drive our sword
through his black heart.
We will pursue him
into the ratholes that he infests.
And finally, we will rid
this city of his kind.
Justice will be done
and will be seen to be done.
Amen.
There's gonna be trouble now, Finn.
You look after yourself, do you hear me?
I'm gonna be going away for a while.
Right. Go on.
Right! Who wants to fucking fight?
Fighting's over.
We're closing up and moving on.
I said, who wants to fucking fight?
My name is Arthur fucking Shelby!
Who dare fight me?
Go home, lad,
before you catch yourself a spanking.
My brother in Digbeth just said
the police are coming down
from Deritend in numbers,
asking for Tommy Shelby by name.
Shit.
I'm gonna have to lie low for a while.
-Why?
-I lost my bargaining power.
This copper, it's just me and him now.
When I get back,
I'm gonna tell you some things.
Harry said the police
are already in Digbeth.
Yeah.
You took a chance coming here. Why?
The police are in the lane, Tommy!
Come with me.
I'm looking for Thomas Shelby.
Never heard of him.
You'll never find him.
Go home.
Perhaps I should ask that question again.
On your knees.
[grunting]
Now, understand this, barman.
I don't care if you live or die.
I don't know!
He left.
With the barmaid.
He left with Grace.
I think they were going to her place.
Call it off.
I don't understand, sir.
We should find the barmaid and--
Call it off!
All of it!
Get in!
It's not much of a place.
It's all right.
You want tea?
Tea? No.
I have rum.
Actually, tea it is.
You want to impress me?
Yes. And do you have a biscuit?
No. They attract mice.
People look different at home.
In what way?
Off guard.
Should I be on my guard?
No, I'm a man who drinks tea.
When the trouble dies down, I'll go.
When will it die down, do you think?
Late, I'd say.
So not until the morning, then.
Yes. I'd say I'll be here till morning.
-You have a gramophone.
-It's broken.
We could still dance.
Yes. Why not?
I know you like to be asked properly.
Grace, can I have this dance?
[Grace] Are you okay?
[Thomas] I don't hear
the shovels against the wall.
[Grace] What shovels?
Will you help me?
[Grace] Help you with what?
With everything.
The whole fucking thing.
Fucking life, business.
I found you.
And you found me.
We'll help each other.
[crying]
Our Father, who art in Heaven.
Hallowed be Thy name.
Thy...
[muffled coughing]
[gasping]
[coughing]
[telephone ringing]
Hello. [clears throat]
Send a telegram to Mr. Churchill.
I have news, very good news.
Tell him the business
I came to attend to is now complete.
I'll be leaving the city.
There's just one matter
I need to tidy up first.
[door opens]
So Polly told you.
Yep.
You should have used a gun.
Are you laughing at me, Tommy?
Yeah.
Just when things
are starting to go right, Arthur,
you try and do this.
Don't you like fancy parties?
Or, um...
Champagne? Or fast cars?
And how about this?
Your name on a business card.
"Shelby Brothers, Limited?
Arthur Shelby. Associate bookmaker."
[Thomas] I just had them picked up
from the printers this morning.
You're one of three shareholders.
Me, you, John.
And according to the law,
we are equal partners.
And it is written in the paperwork
in black and white.
A third, a third, a third.
But the thing is...
Well, me and John,
we quite fancy splitting your share so...
just next time, use a gun, man.
Our men at the station tell me
that copper is leaving town.
We're in the clear.
We're on our way up in the world, brother.
Believe me.